Due to the rain, there's even water leaking inside.
因为下雨 连里面都在漏水
Including the marks, the acting is prearranged.
标记和表演都预先安排好了
The places with puddles are carefully avoided.
小心地避开了有水坑的地方
I've already confirmed that during rehearsal too.
我在排演中也确认了
My entrance, the surrounding set, camera placement, lighting,
我进入的位置、周围的布景 摄影机的位置、灯光
and how I'll appear in the cutaways and cutbacks.
以及我出现在镜头和倒叙中的方式
I have to drill the scene into my head once more.
我得再一次在脑海里回想那一幕
We'll resume the shoot now!
我们现在继续拍摄！
The camera's ready to roll.
摄影机准备好了
Lighting is ready.
灯光准备好了
Mic is ready.
麦克风准备好了
Scene 6, shot 51.
第六场 第51个镜头
Ready, action!
预备 开拍
The sound of the clapperboard rings and the camera begins to roll.
打板声响起 摄影机开拍
The air in the room becomes thick with tension.
房间里的紧张气氛让人透不过气来
As if a whole year had been condensed,
仿佛过了一整年
a heavy yet strong moment begins to pass.
这个沉重、强烈的时刻才开始过去
A very long moment, like my life was being put to the test.
时间很长 仿佛我的生命正在经受考验
My name is Kana Arima.
我的名字叫有马加奈
I was called a genius when I was little, and everyone pampered me.
小时候 大家都说我是天才 都宠着我
You were on TV again!
你又上电视了
Kana, that's amazing!
加奈 太厉害了
Thanks.
谢谢
KANA ARIMA'S GOLDEN AGE
（有马加奈的黄金时代）
But…
但是
Was it my talent or was it the public's whim?
是我天赋异禀还是观众一时兴起？
Or was more effort needed from me?
还是我不够努力？
People will get tired of anything if enough time passes.
时间一长 人就会厌倦
Today, I am called "the expired child star" online.
如今 网上说我是“过气童星”
FORMER GENIUS CHILD STAR
（悲报：前天才童星有马加奈）
It seems I was past my prime after some point in elementary school,
似乎我在小学的某个时候 就已经过了巅峰时期
but I arduously clung on to this industry,
但我没有放弃 还在这一行
and finally grabbed this long-awaited main role.
终于等来了这个期待已久的主角
I want to make this a good piece no matter what.
无论如何 我都希望这部剧拍好
I'll grasp at straws if it's for that purpose.
为此 我会抓住这棵救命稻草
STRAW?
（稻草？）
I know.
我知道
I know this is a shitty piece of work.
我知道这部剧很烂
Acting without basic acting skills.
连基本演技都没有
Already four episodes are released, and most of the audience is disappointed.
这部剧已经播出了四集 大多数观众都很失望
It's been branded with the mark of failure.
它已经被打上了失败的烙印
But it's not too late.
但现在还不算太晚
This part is one of the original story's best scenes.
这部分是原作中最精彩的场景之一
The showdown between the hero and stalker.
英雄与跟踪者的对决
The girl who has never been loved is protected for the first time
从未被爱过的女孩第一次被人保护
and sheds tears.
流下了眼泪
I always cry when I read this part in the manga.
我在漫画里看到这部分的时候 总会哭出来
It's my favorite scene that I always read over and over.
这是我最喜欢的场景 我看了一遍又一遍
If I can just synchronize with Melt to back him up and give the best performance,
如果我能跟梅尔特同步 为他铺垫 发挥自己最好的演技
I'm sure we can still…
我相信我们仍然可以…
Leave me alone!
别烦我！
Stop following me!
别跟着我了！
That sounds like something you'd do.
听起来像是你会做的事情
Synchronize with him…
跟他同步…
But--
但是…
I'm not leaving you alone!
我不会丢下你一个人的！
This is impossible! You can't back this guy up!
不可能 这家伙根本铺垫不了
How can the director and crew think this acting is okay?!
导演和剧组 怎么会认为这样的表演没问题？
Isn't this supposed to be a more tense, scary, and dreadful scene?!
这不该是一个更紧张、 更恐怖、更可怕的场景吗？
Does acting really not matter?
表演真的无所谓吗？
This scene is more…
这个场景更…
The mic's picking up his footsteps from the puddles.
麦克风收录了他踩水坑的脚步声
Should we stop it?
我们要喊停吗？
No.
不要
Let's use it. It sets the mood.
我们用它来增加紧张气氛
This girl isn't the person you think she is.
这女孩不是你想的那种人
A flirty dude like you won't ever match…
像你这样轻浮的人永远都配不上…
Huh… I didn't think he was that good earlier.
我之前没想到他能演这么好
But his acting now seems better than in the rehearsal.
但他现在的表演似乎比排演时更好
I don't have talent like Ai.
我没有爱那样的天赋
I don't have a captivating aura. Nor is my acting really good.
我没有迷人的光环 我的演技也不是很好
That's why, I'll use everything I can.
这就是为什么我会竭尽所能
Props, camera, lighting, actors…
道具、摄影机、灯光、演员…
I'll use all that I can to become like Ai.
我会竭尽所能变得像爱一样
You know, your face is really ugly up close.
天啊 走近了看 你长得真丑
Is that why you edit your photos?
所以你的照片才需要精修吗？
Huh?
什么？
What did you just say?!
你刚才说什么？
Didn't you hear me?
你没听到吗？
I said that woman is not even worth protecting!
我说那个女人根本不值得你保护！
That brat, he's improvising his lines and ignoring the marks…
那个小子 他在即兴创作台词 忽略了标记
Don't stop him.
让他继续
Follow him with Camera 2. Make the light stronger too.
二号摄影机跟着他 灯光再强些
She's an important friend of mine!
她是我很重要的朋友！
It's good.
很好
It looks just like the original story!
跟原作里一模一样
This is one of the best scenes in the manga.
这是漫画里最精彩的场景之一
Stage direction, composition, pacing…
舞台指导、构图、节奏
everything has a meaning.
一切都有意义
I was always good at the book reports where you had to think like the author.
我过去总是很擅长做读书报告 你必须像作者一样思考
As long as you understand the story, you can easily get a passing grade.
只要你理解了这个故事 你就能轻松地通过考试
Here, I set it up for you.
好了 我帮你安排好了
You wanted to do it, right?
你想这么做的 对吧？
Go all out, Kana Arima.
全力以赴吧 有马加奈
It's useless, no matter what you do!
不管你做什么 都无济于事
The highlight of this scene is when the heroine sheds tears.
这场戏的高潮是女主角流泪的时候
Just to make that moment of light shine,
为了让那一刻的光芒闪耀
I'm going to act out the darkness.
我要表演黑暗
Just give up and let this happen!
放弃吧 让我杀了你！
Be scary. Be creepy.
要吓人 令人毛骨悚然
Nobody needs you.
没有人需要你
You gotta live life knowing your place!
你要知道自己的位置
Quit dreaming!
别做梦了！
There's nothing good waiting ahead! Your life's in complete darkness!
前面没有什么好东西等着你 你的生活一片黑暗！
And to finish it off…
最后
If Kana Arima can cry well…
如果有马加奈能哭好…
Still…
还…
Still, there is light.
不过 还是有光明的
Oh yeah, that's her specialty.
是的 她最擅长这个了
My bad.
对不起
My fist hit you, right? I tensed up.
我打到你了吧？我当时很紧张
No need to apologize.
不用道歉
-I moved to get hit on purpose. -What?
-我故意凑上去挨打的 -什么？
Nothing beats acting with emotions.
演戏时投入感情最棒了
That was good acting.
你演得很好
Thanks to that, I'm sure Arima got to go all out.
多亏了那段表演 有马才能使出全力
Jeez, that young kid just messed everything up.
天啊 那小子把一切都搞砸了
Now, we'll have to adjust all our staging plans.
现在 我们必须调整所有的计划
Well, it'll be all right.
没事 这不挺好的
On a set with lots of child actors,
童星众多的片场
you usually rewrite the script while filming anyway.
通常会在拍摄时重写剧本
We're working with young actors, so this should be expected.
我们在跟年轻演员合作 所以这是意料之中的
Looks like it'll become a good scene. I'm sure Kana will be happy.
看起来会成为一场好戏 我相信加奈会很高兴的
Kana, can you go for the final scene now?
加奈 你现在可以 去最后一个场景吗？
Kana?
加奈？
Uh, yes!
可以
Scene 7, shot 310.
第七场 第310个镜头
Ready, action!
预备 开拍！
FACE OF A GIRL WHO FELL IN LOVE WITH THE MAIN CHARACTER
（爱上主角的女孩的脸）
Good morning!
早上好
Uh, if you're gonna sleep, please go to your bed.
如果你要睡觉 就到床上去睡
You'll hurt your back.
这样睡背会疼的
I'll fall into a deep sleep in my bed,
在床上 我会陷入深度睡眠
but I can wake up in about four hours if I sleep on the floor.
但如果我睡在地板上 大约四个小时就醒了
What an unhealthy life hack…
真是不健康的生活认知
Do you have work for us?
你有工作给我们吗？
For now, I put directions for the background
总之我先在第二页的封面和
of page 2's cover page and page 3's panel 1 and 2.
第三页第一组和第二组的背景上 放了说明
Thank you.
谢谢
I'll be watching the Mild Today drama, so let me know when you're almost done.
我会看《今日甜蜜》这部剧 所以你快完成了告诉我
Oh, you still watch it on the day a new episode is released?
你还在新一集播出的那天看吗？
You two aren't watching it?
你们两个不看吗？
Just a little when it began.
刚播出的时候看了一点
I saw up to the second episode.
我看到了第二集
You've both given up, huh?
你们都弃剧了吗？
You don't have to force yourself to watch it.
你不必强迫自己看
You worked so hard to create this piece,
老师您很努力地创作了这部作品
but they made such a mockery of it with that drama.
但他们却用那出戏来嘲弄它
It makes me too angry to watch it.
这让我很生气 我不想看
I already knew from the beginning.
我一开始就知道
That this is an adaptation of a completed manga with no future growth in sight.
这是一部完全改编的漫画 没有发展前景
I should be thankful for it to have any kind of activity.
有动静我就应该感激了
I'm in no position to complain.
我没有资格抱怨
Any manga artist who's had experience with adaptations say,
有过改编经验的漫画家都说
"Don't get your hopes up too high."
“不要抱太大希望”
Every manga artist fantasizes how nice this and that would be,
每个漫画家刚开始都会 幻想着好的效果
but when it's over, they all have a sad expression.
但结束的时候 他们都露出了悲伤的表情
Adaptations are like that, but…
改编就是这样 但是…
Still, there is light.
不过 还是有光明的
Sensei?
老师？
I was able to feel thankful to have gotten the drama adaptation.
我很感激我的作品能被改编成电视剧
Everybody, watch at least the last episode!
大家至少要看最后一集
This is really Mild Today!
这才是《今日甜蜜》
ISN'T THE LAST EPISODE GOOD?
（最后一集不是挺不错的嘛？）
The majority of the audience had already given up
大多数观众已经弃剧了
and only core manga fans or fans of the cast continued to watch the content.
只有核心漫画迷或演员的粉丝还在看
The last episode of Mild Today never went viral or became a hot topic.
《今日甜蜜》的最后一集一直没火 也没有成为热门话题
But it quietly received praise from a small community on the internet.
但它却悄然得到了互联网上 一个小社群的赞扬
THE LAST EPISODE IS A MASTERPIECE!
（最后一集是杰作！）
"MILD FLAVOR TODAY" WRAP PARTY
（ZEDER 《今日甜蜜》杀青派对）
Oh, that actor was in this series too?
那个演员也演过这部剧吗？
When I see everyone like this,
看到大家来参加派对
it makes me realize just how many people were involved.
我才意识到拍一部剧有多少人参与
That's right. There are many people's jobs that are dependent on our acting.
没错 很多人的工作 都依赖于我们的表演
We must achieve good results, so causing a scandal is out of the question.
我们必须取得好的结果 所以不能有丑闻
By the way, you got a girlfriend or anything?
顺便一问 你有女朋友什么的吗？
I don't, so scandals don't concern me.
我没有 所以丑闻与我无关
I see.
这样啊
Hmm.
是吗？
Good work on the filming.
拍得很好
Sensei.
老师
I believe this title was upheld by your acting skills, Ms. Arima.
我相信这部剧是你的演技支撑起来的 有马女士
Thank you so much.
非常感谢
Especially the last episode.
尤其是最后一集
I wish it became like that earlier, but…
真希望能早点像这样 但是…
Hey, Aqua.
喂 阿夸
The last episode had good reviews.
最后一集好评如潮啊
Thank you.
谢谢
The title was tough profit-wise,
这部剧很难盈利
but the goal was to give young talent like you opportunity.
但我们的目标是给予 像你这样的年轻人更好的机会
So I guess we were able to accomplish that.
所以我想我们成功了
After I sent this producer's cigarette butt to DNA testing,
在我把这个制作人的烟蒂 送去做基因检测后
I found out we were complete strangers, so in a way, that was a relief.
我发现我们完全是陌生人 所以在某种程度上 这是一种解脱
However…
然而…
You're with Ichigo Production?
你是莓制作公司的？
In some way,
在某些方面
you have a similar face to Ai.
你跟爱长得很像
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
真的
I used to see her face up close, so there's no mistake there.
我以前经常近距离看她的脸 所以不会有错
"Up close"?
“近距离”吗？
What kind of relation did you have with Ai?
你和爱是什么关系？
I worked with her when I referred her to a fashion magazine model job.
我们曾经共事过 我推荐她去给时尚杂志当模特了
After that, not only did I send her jobs, I took care of her in various aspects.
从那以后 我不仅介绍工作给她 还在各个方面照顾她
Like introducing a good client.
比如介绍好客户给她
Or when she met with a boy in secret from her agency,
或者在她跟她经纪公司 一个男孩秘密会面的时候
I'd tell her a good restaurant.
我会告诉她一家不错的餐厅
Do you know who she was seeing?
你知道她见的是谁吗？
Hmm?
什么？
Are you perhaps Ai's fan?
你是爱的粉丝吗？
You interested in gossip of late celebrities?
你对已故名人的八卦感兴趣吗？
I am.
我是
Then let's see.
这样啊
I don't mind telling you, but let's make it a deal.
我不介意告诉你 但让我们达成协议
Your face is similar to Ai's, it's pretty.
你的脸和爱的很像 很漂亮
Do you have any interest in reality dating shows?
你对恋爱真人秀节目感兴趣吗？
Hey.
喂
How much longer, Ruby?
还要多久 露比？
Jeez, just wait a second, Bro!
等一下 哥
This uniform is cute but difficult to put on.
这套制服很好看 但是不好穿
But it sure is cute!
但真的很好看
Don't make us late on the first day.
我们不能第一天就迟到
Isn't your skirt too short?
你的裙子是不是太短了？
Bro, you've always sounded like an old geezer.
哥 你听起来就像个老古董
Oh yeah!
对了
Mama, we'll be off now.
妈妈 我们要出门了
CONGRATULATIONS ENTRANCE CEREMONY
（开学典礼）
Uh, the next three years, you must all…
接下来的三年 你们必须…
Was entertainment course Class F?
演艺科是F班吗？
Yup. Let's go to class halfway together!
是的 我们一起去上课吧
Congratulations on being admitted, Aqua.
恭喜你被录取了 阿夸
And Ruby.
还有露比
This Youtou High School's class days are flexible compared to other schools,
跟其他学校相比 这个阳东高中的上课时间比较灵活
but if you get bad grades or have bad attendance, you'll be held back.
但如果你成绩不好或出勤率不高 就会被留级
There's not much difference in curriculum either.
课程也没有太大区别
But! That boy is an actor.
但那个男孩是个演员
Those two belong to a major agency's idol group.
这两个人属于一个 大经纪公司的偶像团体
That girl with the huge boobs is a gravure model.
那个大胸的女孩是凹版模特
A voice actor and a streamer… A fashion model and a singer.
那位是配音演员和主播 那边是时装模特和歌手
The ones on the bench are a Kabuki actor and an actress.
板凳上坐着的人 是歌舞伎演员和女演员
Everyone's a celebrity.
每个人都是名人
This is also the high school where the most entertainers gather in Japan.
这也是聚集最多日本艺人的高中
I welcome you, underclassmen.
欢迎你们 学弟、学妹
Welcome to the world of show business!
欢迎来到演艺界
I'm getting nervous!
我越来越紧张了
There's no need to be nervous!
没有必要紧张
This isn't a training school or a film set, it's just a normal school.
这不是培训学校或电影片场 只是一所普通学校而已
So you just have to act normal.
所以正常表现就行
Wow…
天啊
Beauties to my right!
右边是美女
Pretty boys on my left!
左边是帅哥
This is clearly different from my local middle school!
这跟我上的本地初中明显不同
Although, since I've inherited Mama's genes, I shouldn't be losing face-wise.
不过 既然我遗传了妈妈的基因 我不应该丢脸
I will not be overwhelmed!
我不会被压垮的
Look at this girl!
看看这个女孩
STARE
（凝视）
Oh, sorry, I didn't mean to stare.
对不起 我不是故意盯着你看的
I thought, "There's a major beauty here."
我刚在想：“这儿有个大美人啊”
This entertainment course sure has amazing people.
这个演艺科的确藏龙卧虎
Well, so are you.
你也很美啊
Are you a model?
你是模特吗？
I am somewhat.
是的
I'm Minami Kotobuki. Nice to meet you.
我是寿美奈美 见到你很高兴
Minami Kotobuki…
寿美奈美
Oh! You're a gravure idol!
你是凹版偶像
Isn't it inhumane to google someone right in front of them?
当着别人的面就谷歌 是不是很不人道？
Wow, a G cup! How sexy!
G罩杯 好性感啊
Stop!
别说了
I never heard real Kansai dialect before! Are you from Osaka?
我以前从来没听过真正的关西方言 你是大阪人吗？
No, I was born and raised in Kanagawa.
不是 我在神奈川出生和长大
My dialect is just like… my style?
我的方言就像我的风格？
It's a fake Kansai dialect?!
这是假关西方言？
And just like that, I became friends with Minami.
就这样 我跟奈美成为了朋友
What the hell was that?
什么鬼？
Hello.
你好
Well, I'm glad you made a friend.
我很高兴你交到一个朋友
Did you make any friends, Bro?
哥 你交到什么朋友了吗？
Well, I didn't exactly enter this school to make friends.
我进入这所学校并不是为了交朋友
Oh, this is when they couldn't make friends.
这就是交不到朋友的人会说的话
Sorry I asked something cruel.
对不起 我问了一些残忍的事情
You don't have to tell me about class anymore.
你不用再跟我说上课的事了
I have people to chat with at least!
我有人可以聊天
Guys don't establish friendships immediately.
男人不会立即建立友谊
My course is available from middle school unlike yours.
我的课程从中学开始 不像你的
Most friendships are already established, so it takes time to make new ones.
大多数友谊已经建立 因此 建立新的友谊需要时间
It's not like I'm a loner on my first day. Understand?
不是第一天没人理我 明白吗？
Aqua's talking a lot more than usual…
阿夸话比平时多了很多
Minami, could you be friends with Aqua too?
奈美 你能也跟阿夸做朋友吗？
Sure thing.
当然
Don't pass around your friends.
不用介绍你朋友给我
Forget me, just worry about yourself.
别管我 管好你自己就行
Your class is special, so it must be different.
你的班级很特别 所以肯定不一样
That's true.
没错
When I think about how everyone around me is a pro too, it makes me nervous.
当我想到我周围都是专业人士时 就觉得很紧张
There's no need to be nervous!
没有必要紧张
This isn't a training school or a film set, it's just a normal school.
这不是培训学校或电影片场 只是一所普通学校而已
So you just have to act normal.
所以正常表现就行
Ruby…
露比
I heard this same exact line somewhere.
这话我在什么地方听到过
Well, from the looks of the entrance ceremony,
从开学典礼上看
there were many good-looking students, but I barely saw any in the media.
有很多长得漂亮的学生 但我在媒体上几乎没有看到
So you don't need to get nervous.
所以你不需要紧张
No…
不是
There was an incredible person.
有一个不可思议的人
Now, learning materials and the sort will be sold after this…
好了 待会儿会有学习材料 这类的物品销售…
I apologize.
不好意思
I had a promo today on a live show this morning.
我今早在直播节目上有宣传活动
I wanted to at least attend the entrance ceremony, but…
我想着起码要参加开学典礼 但是…
Frill Shiranui…
不知火芙莉露
That's Frill Shiranui…
那是不知火芙莉露
Frill Shiranui was here!
不知火芙莉露来了
She's a hit on that Monday night drama!
她在周一晚上的电视剧里很受欢迎
A multitalented entertainer who can sing, dance and act!
一个多才多艺的艺人 会唱歌、跳舞和表演
When you say "beauty,"
提到“美少女”
Frill Shiranui is the first person who comes to anyone's mind!
不知火芙莉露就是你第一个想到的人
Of course I know of her, but I never knew you were obsessed with her.
我当然知道她 但我从来不知道你很迷她
She's my most fave now.
我现在最喜欢她了
Hmm.
是吗？
"Hmm"? It's the Frill Shiranui!
怎么这态度？那可是不知火芙莉露啊
Not interested.
不感兴趣
My most fave has always been and will always be Ai.
我最喜欢的一直都是爱 永远会是爱
Well, same for me, but…
我也一样 但是…
That's different from this!
这两件事不一样
Oh! Look, there's the real thing!
看啊 是真人
Ah, she's so cute even from a distance!
即使从远处看 她也很漂亮
Seriously, you're just a fan.
你这样子只能当个粉丝啦
You're her classmate, right?
现在你是她的同学吧？
But…
但是…
Huh?
什么？
Hello, Ms. Shiranui.
你好 不知火同学
My sister's in the same class as you.
我妹妹和你同班
Please treat her well.
请善待她
Hey, Bro!
喂 哥
I know you.
我认识你
Weren't you in Mild Today?
你演了《今日甜蜜》吧？
I'm surprised you knew.
你竟然知道
It didn't even become that big of a news.
并不是什么大火的剧
It was talked about on set the other day, so I watched it.
前几天在片场谈论过 所以我看了
It was good.
演得很好
Thanks.
谢谢
I've seen you on the cover of Mid Jump magazine before.
我以前在《中Jump》杂志的 封面上见过你
Was it Ms. Minami?
是奈美小姐吧？
Yes!
是的
Wow…
天啊
They're both being acknowledged by Frill Shiranui!
不知火芙莉露认出了他俩
And you are…
你是…
Um…
那个…
I'm sorry, but what do you do?
对不起 你是做哪一行的？
I'm, um…
我…
doing nothing at the moment…
现在什么也没做
I see.
这样啊
Um…
那个…
Do your best?
加油啊
Miyaemon! Make me into an idol already!
京子 快把我变成偶像！
Don't rush me.
不要催我
We can't set up an audition right away because we want to make an idol group.
我们不能马上安排海选 因为我们想做一个偶像团体
But at this rate…
但按照这个速度…
That girl doesn't really have any work.
那个女孩真的没有任何工作
What? She's just a commoner.
什么？她就是个素人而已
There's a commoner mixed in here.
班里混入一个素人
What a troublesome celebrity fan.
真是个麻烦的明星粉丝
I'll get bullied at this rate!
按照这个速度 我会被欺负的！
To make a proper group, we need to hire a talent scout and undergo proper steps.
为了建立一个合适的团体 我们需要聘请星探并采取适当的步骤
Besides, you can't find cute girls that easily.
而且你不可能轻易就找到美女
Most of the ambitious girls are taken by the major agency auditions too.
大多数雄心勃勃的女孩 也被各大机构的海选所吸引
There's this cute girl with giant boobs called Minami Kotobuki in my class.
我班上有个美女 胸很大 叫寿美奈美
She's in another agency. No!
她有经纪公司 不行
Maybe if she was a freelancer.
她是自由职业者才行
But I don't want any trouble between agencies.
我不想跟其他经纪公司发生冲突
If you want a freelancer, you know one.
如果你想找自由职业者 不是有一个吗？
A freelancer who barely has any work despite being well-known
一个虽然出名却几乎没有任何工作的 自由职业者
and has a cute face.
长着张可爱的脸
Subtitle translation by: Kanami Kitabayashi
字幕翻译：宋宛娇